Register of the Antonina R. von Arnold Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Antonina R. von Arnold papers
1890-1988
YY598
Hoover Institution Archives
(3.6 linear feet) 1 folder, 23 microfilm reels
Diaries, correspondence, writings, financial records, printed matter, photographs, artwork, and memorabilia, relating to Russian émigré affairs, and to social work in California. Includes papers of other members of the Von Arnold family.
Von Arnold, Antonina R., 1896-1988
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
In part, originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biography
A. R. von Arnold, who often went by the nickname Dora, was born in Siedlce (now in Poland) on 26 February 1896 (O. S.). Her father, Roman Apollonovich, then a retired military officer working in the office of the governor-general, volunteered for service during the Russo-Japanese War, following which he remained in Harbin, where he eventually rose to the rank of chief of police. Her mother, born Ekaterina Khristoforovna von Maidel', a dentist by profession, became the founder and director of the Harbin dental school. Antonina had a sister, Liubov', a promising poet who died of appendicitis in Petrograd early in 1917, and a brother, Boris, who became a psychologist in the United States.
Following Boris to the United States in 1923, Antonina tried her hand at business college, but eventually had to fall back on office work to support herself, as well as her mother living in Harbin (her father died in 1930). From work at the Young Women's Christian Association, she moved to the International Institute of San Francisco, making a career in social work and receiving an M.A. in the subject from the University of California at Berkeley in 1942.
An unhappy marriage to a Polish immigrant named Ignatius McGuire was followed by a happier one to the émigré artist Sergey Scherbakoff. Ultimately, Antonina was able to put together enough savings to bring her mother to San Francisco and buy a number of properties, thus achieving the trappings of material success. She died in San Francisco on 8 December 1988.
Chronology
1896 February 26 (O.S.) Born, Sedlets, Russia (Poland)
1916 Death of Liubov' Romanovna von Arnold
1923 Arrived in the United States
1929 Death of Roman Apollonovich von Arnold
1937 B.A., University of California, Berkeley, California
1942 M.A., Social Welfare, University of California, Berkeley, California
1963 Death of Ekaterina Khristoforovna von Arnold
1964 Death of Boris von Arnold
1967 Death of Sergey Scherbakoff
1988 December 8 Died, San Francisco, California
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the papers of Antonina Romanovna von Arnold, as well as papers relating to and produced by her father, mother, sister, brother, and other family members. Of particular interest are von Arnold's diaries and her untitled family chronicle (SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, Box 12). Together with the material in her biographical file and correspondence, these provide an in-depth view of the personal experience of a Russian immigrant in the United States. The FAMILY FILE contains the reminiscences of von Arnold's father, Roman Apollonovich, the police chief of Harbin, and materials on the career and life of his wife, Ekaterina Khristoforovna, founder and principal of the Harbin Dental College. Also of importance are the papers of von Arnold's second husband, the artist Sergey Scherbakoff (SERGEY SCHERBAKOFF FILE).
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Von Arnold family.; Russia.; Russians--United States.; Social service--California.; United States.
- Biographical File, 1904-1985 (Box 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Birth certificate, educational, employment and financial records, identity papers, notebooks, real estate documents, war ration books, will, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Diaries, 1914-1977 (Box 3-6)
  Daily entries, notes, short stories and inserts, arranged chronologically
- Correspondence, 1914-1986 (Box 7-10)
  Cards and letters, arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1915-[1973] (Box 11-14)
  Articles, memoirs, poetry, short stories, and thesis, arranged chronologically by title
- Family File, 1890-1977 (Box 14-18)
  Papers of other members of the von Arnold family, arranged alphabetically by name and therein by physical form
- Sergey Scherbakoff File, 1912-1967 (Box 18-20)
  Biographical file, correspondence, subject file, and writings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Subject File, 1968-1970 (Box 20)
  Minutes of meetings of the Community Children's Nursery, 1968-1970
- Printed Matter, 1930-1979 (Box 20)
  Brochures, clippings, leaflets, offprints, programs
- Oversize File, and., 1919-1942 undated (Box 21)
  Diplomas, notes, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Artwork, n.d. (Box 22-23)
  Includes sketches, drawings, watercolors, etchings and other forms of artwork by the von Arnold clan (especially Antonina), Scherbakoff and Frontinskaia
- Photographs, 1800s-1980s (Box 23-27)
  Albums, negatives, prints and scrapbook depicting the von Arnold clan, Scherbakoff, Frontinskaia and miscellaneous people and places
- Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 27)
  Includes handicrafts, placards, lithographic plates, and items of clothing
- Financial Records, 1942-1988 (Box 28)
  Bank statements, bills, receipts, tax records and similar matter. Not filmed due to large volume and insignificant historical value
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1904-1985 (Box 1)
  - Addresses and telephone numbers.
    General note
    See Notes
  - Birth certificate (Folder 1: 1)
  - Calling cards (Folder 1: 2)
  - Educational records.
    See also Notes for lecture notes and class assignments, and OVERSIZE FILE/Diplomas
    - General. (Folder 1: 3)
      Includes certificates of matriculation, report cards, student identification
    - Correspondence, 1931-1944 (Folder 1: 4)
      Primarily with officials and faculty of the University of California, Berkeley. Includes letters of recommendation for von Arnold
  - Employment records. (Folder 1: 5)
    Includes applications for work, correspondence, and resumes
  - Financial records. (Folder 1: 6-8)
    This folder contains a portion of von Arnold's financial records that reveal her financial standing at various points in her life. More voluminous records, including bank statements, income tax returns, bills, receipts, estimates, correspondence with contractors and real estate agents regarding purchase and sale of property have been relegated to the unfilmed FINANCIAL RECORDS series at the rear of the collection
  - Genealogical records.
    See FAMILY FILE/General
  - Identity papers. (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Includes affidavits, certificate of naturalization, passports, residence certificate, and other papers
  - Marriage certificate. (Folder 2: 2)
    Includes divorce decree
  - Notes. (Folder 2: 3-7)
    Includes case work and lecture notes, class assignments, reminders, lists of things to do and addresses and telephone numbers
  - Real estate documents. (Box-folder 3: 1)
    Includes contracts, deeds, escrow statements, insurance records, leases, license certificates, lot maps, and other matter pertaining to von Arnold's and her husband's properties
  - War ration books (Folder 3: 2)
  - Will. (Folder 3: 3)
    Includes letters to Theodore S. Olferieff, 1969-1970, indicating proposed measures to be taken in the event of von Arnold's death
  - Miscellany (Folder 3: 4)
- DIARIES, 1914-1977
  See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/"My American Story" for diary excerpts and yearly summaries and conclusions
  Daily entries, notes, short stories and inserts, arranged chronologically.
  - General - "Selected pages"
    - Construction of summer house on Russian River, California, 1950-1955 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Sergey Scherbakoff and his death
      - 1945-1965 (Folder 3: 6)
      - 1966-1972 (Folder 3: 7)
  - 1914 (Folder 3: 8)
  - 1915 (Folder 3: 9)
  - 1916 (Folder 3: 10)
  - 1917-1918 (Folder 3: 11)
  - 1918-1919 (Folder 3: 12)
  - 1920-1921 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - ., 1921-1922 (Folder 4: 2)
    Includes entries from 1925 written into the 1921 diary
  - 1923 (Folder 4: 3)
  - 1923-1928 (Folder 4: 4)
  - 1936-1941 (Folder 4: 5)
  - 1942 (Folder 4: 6)
  - 1943 (Box 5)
    - January-May (Folder 5: 1)
    - June-December (Folder 5: 2)
  - 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 3)
  - 1946-1951 (Folder 5: 4)
  - 1952-1960 (Folder 5: 5)
  - 1961-1964 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - 1965-1967 (Folder 6: 2)
  - 1968 (Folder 6: 3)
  - 1969 (Folder 6: 4)
  - 1970 (Folder 6: 5)
  - 1971-1972 (Folder 6: 6)
  - 1973-1977 (Folder 6: 7)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1986 (Box 7)
  For correspondence relating exclusively to von Arnold's education and employment, see BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Educational records and Employment records
  - General
    - Undated (Folder 7: 1-2)
    - 1915-1986 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Unidentified
    - General, and, 1914-1957 undated (Folder 7: 4)
    - Relatives, and., 1917-1920 undated (Folder 7: 5)
      Includes letters from von Arnold's grandmother, uncle, and aunt
  - Alderman, Jennie, 1947-1948 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Arnold, Boris Romanovich von, and., 1915-1964 undated (Folder 7: 7)
    Includes cards and letters from Boris's first and second wives, Gaby and Claire
  - Arnold, Ekaterina Khristoforovna von (Box 8)
    - Incoming
      - 1914-1929 (Folder 8: 1)
      - 1930-1936 (Folder 8: 2)
      - 1937-1949 (Folder 8: 3)
      - 1950-1960 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Outgoing
      - Undated (Folder 8: 5)
      - 1931-1960 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Arnold, Gunnar von, 1965-1977 (Folder 9: 2)
    Includes attachments relating to von Arnold family history (genealogical tree, coat of arms and copies of encyclopedia entries)
  - Arnold, Liubov' Romanovna von, and, 1916-1917 undated (Folder 9: 3)
  - Arnold, Roman Apollonovich von, 1915-1929 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Berezov, Rodion, and, 1958 undated (Folder 9: 5)
  - Blium (Blum), N., 1942-1952 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Borzov, Nikolai Viktorovich, and, 1942-1949 undated (Folder 9: 7)
  - Burns, Lilian, and, 1933-1958 undated (Folder 9: 8)
  - Clemens, Florence, n.d. (Folder 9: 9)
  - Cornin, Jon and Zena (Folder 9: 10)
  - Davidson, Charles, and, 1970-1974 undated (Folder 9: 11)
  - Dennis, Hazel A., and, 1923 undated (Folder 9: 12)
  - Dickinson, Elizabeth, n.d. (Folder 9: 13)
  - Dombrovskii, Genrikh Gratsianovich, and, 1914-1917 undated (Folder 9: 14)
  - Domina (?), M., 1914-1915 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Gershgorin, V., 1952 (Folder 9: 16)
  - Gorgopa, Oleg, 1966-1980 (Folder 9: 17)
    Includes biographical note
  - Grace, Olga, 1974-1976 (Folder 9: 18)
  - Gul'shin, Maksim Efimovich, n.d. (Folder 9: 19)
    Includes postcard with Gul'shin's photograph in WWI military uniform
  - Gusel'nikova, E., 1954-1978 (Folder 9: 20)
  - Harding, Harold, n.d. (Folder 9: 21)
  - Hartwell, Marian (?), n.d. (Folder 9: 22)
  - Hill, J. G., and, 1918 undated (Folder 9: 23)
  - Isaenko, Evgeniia Sergeevna, 1946-1967 (Folder 9: 24)
  - James, Oliver Clemens, and, 1932-1944 undated (Folder 9: 25)
  - Jay, Lucy Churchill, 1925-1939 (Folder 9: 26)
  - Jones, Lydia Grey, and, 1959-1978 undated (Folder 9: 27)
  - Kapilos (?), V., 1932-1942 (Folder 9: 28)
  - Khorvat, Kamilla, and, 1948-1952 undated (Folder 9: 29)
  - Kragg (?), Ida, 1931-1955 (Folder 9: 30)
  - Lushnicoff (Lushnikov), Irina and Nikolai, 1952-1981 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - McGuire, Ignatius
    - Incoming, and, 1936-1945 undated (Folder 10: 2)
    - Outgoing, and, 1936-1942 undated (Folder 10: 3)
  - Malozemoff, Elizabeth, and, 1944 undated (Folder 10: 4)
  - Mashin, Nina, 1963-1979 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Myers, O., 1964-1967 (Folder 10: 6)
  - National League for American Citizenship, 1938 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Olferieff, Theodore S.
    See BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Will
  - Oppenheim, David A., 1950-1951 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Perry, Isabella (aka Isabella Hessel and Isabella Kramer), and, 1929-1966 undated (Folder 10: 9)
  - Popov, Sergei Aristarkhovich, 1953-1954 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Rachinskaia, E., and, 1931-1978 undated (Folder 10: 11)
  - Repina, Mariia, 1963-1966 (Folder 10: 12)
  - Riasanovsky, Nina (aka Nina Fedorova), 1958-1959 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Sanderson, Edith M., and, 1939-1973 undated (Folder 10: 14)
  - Schilling, Else, and, 1933-1936 undated (Folder 10: 15)
  - Schmidt, Frijos J., 1947-1953 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Scherbakoff, Sergey, n.d. (Folder 10: 17)
  - Spurgeon, Elizabeth, 1932-1933 (Folder 10: 18)
  - Stauffer, Norma H., and, 1938-1975 undated (Folder 10: 19)
  - Sultan, Emrullah, 1954 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Taran, Konstantin, 1915 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Thompson, Dr., and, 1931-1935 undated (Folder 10: 22)
  - Venable, Rosalee, and, 1937-1945 undated (Folder 10: 23)
  - Volkmann, Johanna, and, 1936-1944 undated (Folder 10: 24)
  - Vonsovich, Vera, 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 25)
  - Vuich, Ivan, 1920(?) (Folder 10: 26)
  - Wilson, Kate, 1947-1972 (Folder 10: 27)
  - Zerensufer, Vladimir, n.d. (Folder 10: 28)
    Includes photograph of Zerensufer in WWI military uniform
  - Zvonnikova, A., 1954 (Folder 10: 29)
    Includes letter to N. Zvonnikov from Mrs. Ehrenford, 1954
  - Miscellany, and., 1973-1974 undated (Folder 10: 30)
    Empty envelopes
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1915-[1973] (Box 11)
  - General
    - General, and., 1915-1950s undated (Folder 11: 1-2)
      See also DIARIES for plays and sketches included in von Arnold's diary notebooks and OVERSIZE FILE for additional notes
      Includes brief plays, short stories and sketches, notes and fragments.
    - Correspondence, and., 1934-1957 undated (Folder 11: 3)
      Relates to von Arnold's literary activity (submissions and correspondence courses)
    - Poetry, and., 1934-[1943] undated (Folder 11: 4)
      Includes original poetry and translations of Russian poetry into English. Holograph and typescript
  - "Bozh'ia volia,", n.d. (Folder 11: 5)
    Holograph
  - "Concept of Employability in the Light of Unemployment Relief Experience of 1930-1940,", n.d. (Folder 11: 6)
    Typescript
  - "Cultural Conflict in Case Work Situations,", n.d. (Folder 11: 7)
    Typescript. Includes an early draft entitled, "Children of Foreign Parentage"
  - "Dom v derevnie,", n.d. (Folder 11: 8)
  - "Four Mornings,", n.d. (Folder 11: 9)
    Typescript. Includes early draft entitled "Observing a Friend Going on a Trip"
  - "From the Roof of the Vatican,", n.d. (Folder 11: 10)
  - "Home Leaving,", n.d. (Folder 11: 11)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Iazyk, kak orudie cheloviecheskago myshleniia,", n.d. (Folder 11: 12)
  - Introduction to a speech by Mrs. Lensky, n.d. (Folder 11: 13)
  - "Kanada iz okna vagona," Novaia zaria, n.d. (Folder 11: 14)
    Printed copy
  - "The Last Ten Years of Our Mother,", n.d. (Folder 11: 15)
    Typescript and notes
  - "Mariia,", n.d. (Folder 11: 16)
    Typescript. Includes prologue entitled "Istoriia odnogo spektaklia"
  - "The Melting Pot."
    See "Russkaia missis Dzhons," Novaia zaria, 1953 August 15
  - "Nasha Amerika,", n.d. (Folder 11: 17)
  - "O Man'chzhurii, staroobriadtsakh i tigrakh," Novaia zaria, n.d. (Folder 11: 18)
  - "Poetessa-emigrantka,", n.d. (Folder 11: 19)
  - "A Russian Story About an Irish Love,", n.d. (Folder 12: 1)
  - "The Story of Our Uncle Vladimir,", n.d. (Folder 12: 2)
    Typescript. Includes early draft entitled "Uncle George's Story"
  - "Tales of the Silent Generation,", n.d. (Folder 12: 3)
  - "That Was the Spirit of the Pioneers,", n.d. (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Those Shanghai Women,", n.d. (Folder 12: 5)
  - Untitled family chronicle, n.d. (Folder 12: 6)
  - "What Is a Good Adoption Program in a County?", n.d. (Folder 12: 7)
  - "Women,", n.d. (Folder 12: 8)
  - "Poputchiki,"., 1917 October (Folder 12: 9)
  - "Assotsiatsiia v myshlenii,"., 1919 (Folder 12: 10)
  - "The Concept of Employability and the Rehabilitation of Unemployment Relief Clients," M.A. thesis, University of California, 1937 (Folder 12: 11)
  - "A Brief Study of the Russian Students in the University of California,"., 1937 April 30 (Folder 12: 12)
  - "Organizations of the Russian Community in San Francisco,"., 1938 April 29 (Folder 12: 13)
  - "Agricultural Laborers on the Rolls of SRA in California,"., 1939 December (Folder 12: 14)
  - "Materials for the Reorganization of the Public Welfare of California with a Tentative Plan,"., 1940 December 11 (Folder 12: 15)
  - "Narcissism and the Sense of Inferiority,"., 1942 February (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
    Typescript (2 drafts) and notes
  - "Russians in San Francisco,"., 1943 January (Folder 13: 3)
  - Newspaper articles on Russian émigrés bound together, Russkaia zhizn', 1946 November 15 - 1947 March 7 (Folder 13: 4)
  - "Watercolors at Labaudt Gallery," letter to the editor, 1949 June 16 (Folder 13: 5)
    Typescript and note
  - "The Most Unforgettable Character I Have Met,"., 1953 January 7 (Folder 13: 6)
    Typescript. Includes correspondence and holograph draft entitled "The Most Remarkable Character"
  - "Russkaia missis Dzhons," Novaia zaria, 1953 August 15 (Folder 13: 7)
    Printed copy. Includes English typed translations entitled "Russian Mrs. Jones" and "The Melting Pot"
  - "Moskva likuiushchaia," Novaia zaria, [1970] (Folder 13: 8)
  - "Sovremennyi Kiev," Novaia zaria, [1970] (Folder 13: 9)
  - "Ialta," Novaia zaria, 1970 August 1 (Folder 13: 10)
  - "My American Story,", [1973]
    - Notes (Folder 13: 11)
    - Typescript (Folder 13: 12-13)
    - Typescript (Box-folder 14: 1)
- FAMILY FILE, 1890-1977
  Papers of other members of the von Arnold family. For their correspondence with Antonina, see CORRESPONDENCE
  - General. Information on the von Arnold and related families. (Folder 14: 2)
    Includes death certificate for Baroness Liubov' Iakovlevna Maidel', 1921
  - Arnold, Boris Romanovich von (brother)
    - Biographical file. (Folder 14: 3)
      Includes address book, birth certificate, clipping about, and miscellany
    - Correspondence
      - Arnold, Ekaterina Khristoforovna von (letters from), 1923-1954 (Folder 14: 4)
      - Arnold, Roman Apollonovich von (letters from), 1923-1929 (Folder 14: 5)
      - Arnold, Werner von, 1964 (Folder 14: 6)
        Includes family tree
      - Scherbakoff, Sergey, n.d. (Folder 14: 7)
    - Writings
      - "Liudi iz Kharbinskago svieta,", n.d. (Folder 14: 8)
      - "Malan'ia,", n.d. (Folder 14: 9)
      - "Recollections About the Russian Counter-Revolution,", n.d. (Folder 14: 10)
      - "Zhar-ptitsa,", n.d. (Folder 14: 11)
      - "Rorschach Signs in the Selection of Outstanding Young Male Mechanical Workers," The Journal of Psychology, 1944 (Folder 14: 12)
      - "Personality Needs as a Determinant of Vocational Choice and Their Relationship to School and Work Achievement,"., 1954 February 26 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Arnold, Ekaterina Khristoforovna von (mother)
    - Biographical file
      - Addresses and certificates of gratitude (Folder 14: 14)
      - Calling cards (Folder 14: 15)
      - Clippings about or mentioning E. Kh. von Arnold (Folder 14: 16)
      - Curriculum vitae (Folder 14: 17)
      - Death certificate (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Diplomas (Folder 15: 2)
      - Immigration records. (Folder 15: 3)
        Includes voluminous correspondence between E. Kh. von Arnold, A. R. von Arnold, government and non-governmental agencies and officials relating to E. Kh. von Arnold's admission to the United States in 1954
      - Inventory of archive (Folder 15: 4)
      - Notes (Folder 15: 5)
      - Miscellany (Folder 15: 6)
    - Diaries, 1896-1903 (Folder 15: 7)
      Relates to her three children Correspondence
      - General, and., 1934-1961 undated (Folder 15: 8)
        Includes two notebooks containing holograph drafts of letters, primarily to Boris von Arnold, as well as practice exercises for citizenship examinations
      - Unidentified, and, 1956-1958 undated (Folder 15: 9)
      - Aleksandrova, E. G., 1955-1956 (Folder 15: 10)
      - Arnold, Boris and Claire von (letters from), and, 1940-1962 undated (Folder 15: 11)
      - Arnold, John von, n.d. (Folder 16: 1)
      - Berezov, Rodion, 1957-1963 (Folder 16: 2)
        Includes poetry dedicated to E. Kh. von Arnold
      - Gusel'nikova, E. N., 1954-1955 (Folder 16: 3)
        Includes third-party correspondence
      - Kratze, M., 1961 (Folder 16: 4)
      - Lushnikov, Nikolai and Irina, 1953-1958 (Folder 16: 5)
      - Maidel', Liubov' Iakovlevna, n.d. (Folder 16: 6)
      - Myers, Olga, 1955-1963 (Folder 16: 7)
      - Nebushenkova, N. A., 1955-1960 (Folder 16: 8)
      - Nikol'skaia, T., 1960-1962 (Folder 16: 9)
      - Rachinskaia, E., and, 1954-1963 undated (Folder 16: 10)
      - Reihberg, Anta V., n.d. (Folder 16: 11)
      - Repina, N., and, 1955-1960 undated (Folder 16: 12)
      - Schmidt, Maria, and, 1949-1952 undated (Folder 16: 13)
      - Zhidialis, Maria and Edward, and, 1961 undated (Folder 16: 14)
    - Writings
      - General
        - Newspaper columns on dental news and hygiene (Folder 16: 15)
        - Poetry. (Folder 16: 16)
          May include poetry by Antonina von Arnold and others
      - "Dostizheniia i tsieli sovremennago zubovrachevaniia,", n.d. (Folder 16: 17)
      - "Tak budet krasit'sia vsia russkaia strana: K 175-lietnemu iubileiu Smol'nago Instituta," Golos emigrantov, 1939 May 21 (Folder 16: 18)
    - Subject file - First Dental College of Harbin, China. Compilation of materials for its history (Folder 16: 19)
  - Arnold, Liubov Romanovna von (sister)
    - Biographical file, 1897-1916 (Folder 16: 20)
      Includes birth and death certificates, school records, identity papers, will and final letter to parents, and information on the circumstances of her death
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 17: 1)
      Includes letters to her mother and grandmother
    - Diaries, [1915]-1916 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Writings, and., 1913-1916 undated (Folder 17: 3-5)
      Primarily poetry, with a few plays and a short story
  - Arnold, Roman Apollonovich von (father)
    - Biographical file, 1890-1954 (Folder 17: 6)
      Includes genealogical records, military service records, decorations, correspondence relating to R. A. von Arnold's arrest in 1918 and death notices
    - Correspondence, 1914-1917 (Folder 17: 7)
      Unidentified individuals
    - Writings
      - "Rossiia v proshlom,", n.d.
        - Holograph (Folder 17: 8)
        - Typescript (2 drafts) (Folder 18: 1-2)